

Contact

Personal website

✓ daniel.ordonez@upc.edu

+34 603 63 96 62

in linkedin.com/in/danfoa

github.com/Danfoa

Profile

I am a Colombian engineer with a strong passion for Robotics and Computer Science. My research interests are machine learning and optimal control specially applied to legged locomotion, dexterous manipulation, reinforcement learning, and most applications aimed to close the performance gap between animals and robotic systems. Born in: 1995

LANGUAGES

Spanish English German **Mother Tongue** C1 (TOEFL) Intermediate - B2

Programming

ADVANCED













ADVANCED











INTERMEDIATE





References

Dr. Francesc Moreno-Noguer

BARCELONA TECH Tel: (+34) 34 934010775 fmoreno@iri.upc.edu

Dr. Mario Martin

BARCELONA TECH Tel: (+34) 93 413 7883 mmartin@cs.upc.edu

Dr. Carl-Helmut Coulon

INVITE GMBH Tel: (+49) 214 312 03125 carl-helmut.coulon@bayer.com

Daniel Felipe Ordoñez Apraez

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence - B.Sc. Mechatronics Engineering

EDUCATION

2019-2021 Barcelona

Universitat Politècnica de Catalunya - Barclona Tech

M.Sc. in Artificial Intelligence Spain 💡

Thesis: Learning to run naturally: guiding policies with the Spring-Loaded In-

verted Pendulum

2013-2018 Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Bogota B.Sc. in Mechatronics Engineering

Exchange semester: Informatics faculty of the Technique University of Munich

EXPERIENCE

Colombia 💡

2021-Present 2019-2020

Barcelona Spain **Q**

Institut de Robòtica i Informàtica Industrial (IRI-CSIC)

ASSISTANT RESEARCHER STUDENT RESEARCHER

Research Projects: Learning realistic legged locomotion with Reinforcement Learning techniques and template dynamical models - Interactive Perception-Action-Learning for Modelling Objects (IPALM) - Human hand motion forecasting and pose discretization

INVITE GmbH research center (TU Dortmund & Bayer Technology Services)

2018-2019 2017-2018

Cologne Germany 9 JUNIOR RESEARCH ASSISTANT

ROBOTICS INTERN Research project: Manipulation of plastic bags using a two-arm robot with 3D

vision and force feedback.

- Project Presentation Video - EP-Patent: Autonomous Drum and Inliner Handling - Expected resolution 2022

- Final work certificate

2016-2017

Bogotá Colombia 💡 Busescool SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Developed front and back-end of administrative tools that allowed the control and monitoring of Busescool's realtime database and services

Mar-Dec 2016

Bogotá Colombia 💡

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

ENGINEERING FACULTY TUTOR

Courses tutored: - Data structures and algorithms - Numerical methods - Control theory - Object-oriented programming - Basic programming

Publications - Patents

- Ordoñez Apraez, D. F Aqudo, Antonio Moreno, Francesc Martin, Mario (2022). An Adaptable Approach to Learn Realistic Legged Locomotion without Examples. Submitted to ICRA 2022 (pending review) - Accepted Poster at Deep Learning Barcelona Symposium 2021
- Ordoñez Apraez, D. F., INVITE GmbH., Bayer A.G. (2022). Autonomous Drum and Inliner Handling. Pending European Patent.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- Implementation of DeepMind's Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning model of commonpool resource appropriation
- Measuring Parkinson's disease progression
- Developed approach for The Semantic Evaluation (SemEval) challenge 2012
- Protein evolution/structure prediction Design of custom permutation invariant CNN layers targeted at processing protein's Multiple Sequence Alignments
- Transition INVITE's robotics research platform to ROS.
- Mechanic, electronic and control design of a Micromouse
- Mechanic and control design of a two-DoF RP robot
- Control design of a 1-DoF air propelled system experimenting with different robust control techniques (H_{∞} , Slide Mode Control and Adaptive control)

Awards

2019 Top 1% score on the Colombian Saber-Pro national exam, which evaluates all students near graduation of a higher education's degree

Selected to the Colombian COLFUTURO's recruitment of talent program and awarded 2019 scholarship/loan for higher education

University tuition exception 2015